Mildred P. French Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Mildred P. French Papers.
undated, 1930-1968.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Reearch Center.
French, Mildred P.
.25 cubic feet.
Mildred P. French was the Dean of Women and Home Economics at the University of Connecticut from 1928 until her retirement in 1953.
MSS20010041
Biography
Mildred Pearl French was born 6 December 1891 in La Grande, Oregon. She attended the Pratt Institute (1915, B.S.) and the University of Idaho before receiving her graduate degree at Columbia University (1925, A.M.). French was employed in various positions at Kansas State College, University of Indiana, and Columbia University before her appointment as Dean of Women and Dean of the School of Home Economics at the University of Connecticut in 1928.
Upon her retirement in 1953, Miss French moved to Cheney, Washington, where she continued to be active in community.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, clippings, notes, momentoes, programs and photographs. The vast majority of the materials concern Miss French's retirement, travels and subsequent relocation to Washington State.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and are housed separately [Please ask for assistance]:
Photographs and postcards (2001-0041).
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
French, Mildred P.
Places:
Storrs (Conn.)--Education--Universities and colleges.
Occupation:
College teachers--Connecticut.; College administrators.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.; Photocopies.; Notes.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The materials in the collection were in the possession of Ms. Marilyn Azevedo, Miss French's niece. In 2000, Ms. Azevedo sent them to Dr. Irene Brown in the School of Family Studies, who in turn transferred them to the University Archives in May 2001.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the University in 2000 by Miss French's niece, Marilyn Azevedo.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1930-1968
  - Bermuda Trip, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Information, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, 1965, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, undated, 1953-1954, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, undated, 1930, 1953, 1957, 1964 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (29), undated, 1934-1964
  - Postcards (5), undated
  - Programs, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Retirement--Notes and cards, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Student Union, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 8)